Oswego Valley League of Women Voters Collection
State University of New York at Oswego
Oswego Valley League of Women Voters Collection
1953 - 1979
The collection contains correspondence, publications from local, state and national chapters, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous other items of government programs in the region. The key documents are the organization’s minutes and correspondence, as well as the local chapter’s newsletter the “Valley Voter” (1966-1978).
18 boxes 7 linear feet
League of Women Voters (Oswego County, NY)
State University of New York at Oswego Penfield Library 7060 State Route 104 Oswego, New York 13126-3599
2015.103.0001
Collection is open to the public.
The Oswego Valley League of Women Voters was organized on a provisional basis from its inception during September 1964, through October 1967. At that time the local chapter became a fully recognized part of the state and national League of Women Voters. Although there were difficulties from the start due to a small membership and the separation of interests of women from Oswego and Fulton, the chapter remained active until February 1979.
During these years the group participated in discussions on many topics of local and national concern. Among these were energy, the environment, governmental planning and organization, schools and pollution. Besides holding meetings to consider these matters, the local league annually strived to increase voters' awareness about candidates and issues.
The league sponsored a public forum, Meet Your Candidates, where candidates could answer questions from the League of Women Voters and the audience and prepared a newspaper section which contained candidates' views about local issues. Due to a declining membership the Oswego Valley League of Women Voters disbanded in February 1979.
League of Women Voters (Oswego County, NY); Women--Societies and clubs; Women's studies--United States; Women's studies--New York (State)--Oswego; Jackim, Lois; Shoffner, Ellen B.; Sidwell, Anne
The Oswego Valley League of Women Voters Collection reflects both the organization and workings of the chapter in its records and the scope of its interests through material collected on subjects of concern. Due to the subject emphasis of the collection folders frequently contain several types of material ranging from correspondence to publications. Especially Series II through VII folders are likely to contain publications and reports from either the national or state League of Women Voters organizations or both; non-league publications; newspaper clippings and/or magazine articles; publicity releases of the local chapter; material pertaining to local programs; and correspondence.
The basic organization of the collection retains the way files were kept by the Oswego Valley League of Women Voters. Minor rearrangement was done to bring together subject-related material and to remove duplication. The reverse chronological order has been retained. Therefore, in all folders the most recent item will be on the top. In a few cases, most noticeably correspondence related to preparation of the newspaper section on candidates, items are arranged in folders by subject as well as chronologically.
- I. League of Women Voters, 1958 - 1979 (Box-folder 01-01)
  League of Women Voters - Local By-laws, 1977-1972. Local, state and national
  - A. Local, 1964 - 1979
    - By-laws, 1977-1972, 1972 - 1977 (Box-folder 01-01)
    - Minutes February 6, 1979 - January 25, 1971, 1971 - 1979 (Box-folder 01-02)
      League of Women Voters - Local Minutes February 6, 1979 - January 25, 1971. Executive Board: calendar for 1974 (after February 28, 1974), 1973-1974 (after July 18, 1973) and 1975-1976.
    - Minutes November 23, 1970 - March 18, 1965, 1965 - 1970 (Box-folder 01-03)
      League of Women Voters - Local Minutes November 23, 1970 - March 18, 1965, Executive Board includes lists of officers.
    - Annual meetings, 1978-1966, 1966 - 1978 (Box-folder 01-04)
      League of Women Voters - Local Annual meetings, 1978-1966 Includes: publicity clippings; programs; correspondence; Valley Voter (April 1978); speech by Natasha Dykman given at 1978 meeting
    - General membership meetings, 1964 - 1969 (Box-folder 01-05)
      League of Women Voters - Local General membership meetings, 1979; March 19, 1969 -- September 29, 1964. Includes minutes; abstracts
    - Annual reports, 1979-1967, 1967 - 1979 (Box-folder 01-06)
      League of Women Voters - Local Annual reports, 1979-1967. Forms prepared for state league
    - Budget, 1977-1966, 1966 - 1977 (Box-folder 01-07)
      League of Women Voters - Local Budget, 1977-1966. Includes: proposed budgets; state league reports; national league publications; page from 1976 annual report.
    - Treasurer's reports, 1979-1969, 1969 - 1979 (Box-folder 01-08)
      League of Women Voters - Local Treasurer's reports, 1979-1969 Includes: completed monthly and quarterly report forms; state league treasurer reports; correspondence; notes on workshop for treasurers (June 1978)
    - Membership, n.d. (Box-folder 02-01)
      League of Women Voters - Local Membership Includes: publicity material; state board reports; lists of potential members; correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1979-1970, 1970 - 1979 (Box-folder 02-02)
      League of Women Voters - Local Correspondence, 1979-1970 Includes: letters to the editor (clippings)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1967, 1967 - 1969 (Box-folder 02-03)
      League of Women Voters - Local Correspondence, 1969-1967
    - Correspondence, 1966-1964, 1964 - 1966 (Box-folder 02-04)
      League of Women Voters - Local Correspondence, 1966-1964
    - Media and publicity (Box-folder 02-05)
      League of Women Voters - Local Media and publicity Includes: clippings; news releases; league and non-league publications on publicity; OVLWV survevy of local media concerning league coverage, 1975.
    - Fund campaigns, 1977-1965, 1965 - 1977 (Box-folder 02-06)
      League of Women Voters - Local Fund campaigns, 1977-1965 Includes: publicity releases; correspondence; lists of potential donors; reports of solicitors; clippings
    - Fund raising (Box-folder 03-01)
      League of Women Voters - Local Fund raising Printed league and non-league materials
    - Valley Voter, 1978-1974, 1974 - 1978 (Box-folder 03-02)
      League of Women Voters - Local Valley Voter, 1978-1974 Newsletter
    - Valley Voters, 1973-1966, 1966 - 1973 (Box-folder 03-03)
      League of Women Voters - Local Valley Voters, 1973-1966 Newsletter
    - Radio show scripts, 1972-1966, 1966 - 1972 (Box-folder 03-04)
      League of Women Voters - Local Radio show scripts, 1972-1966 Prepared by OVLWV (Oswego Valley League of Women Voters)
  - B. State, 1965 - 1979
    - New York State Voter, 1979-1965 (incomplete), 1965 - 1979 (Box-folder 03-05)
      League of Women Voters - State New York State Voter, 1979-1965 (incomplete)
    - State board reports, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 03-06)
      League of Women Voters - State State board reports, 1978-1979
    - State programs, 1979-1973, 1973 - 1979 (Box-folder 03-07)
      League of Women Voters - State State programs, 1979-1973 Material from state league and other local chapters
    - State pamphlet for local programs, June 1979 (Box-folder 03-08)
      League of Women Voters - State State pamphlet for local programs, June 1979
    - Material about local bulletins, 1973-1971, 1971 - 1973 (Box-folder 04-01)
      League of Women Voters - State Material about local bulletins, 1973-1971 Mainly state board reports.
  - C. National, n.d.
    - Board reports, 1979-1976, 1976 - 1979 (Box-folder 04-02)
    - National programs, 1977-1966, 1966 - 1977 (Box-folder 04-03)
      League of Women Voters - National National programs, 1977-1966 Reports: local, state and national; publications about League of Women Voters Education Fund, Overseas Education Fund of the League of Women Voters, and the Foundation for Citizen Education; Oswego Valley League of Women Voters reports to national league.
    - Lobbying, 1977-1970, 1970 - 1977 (04-04)
      League of Women Voters - National Lobbying, 1977-1970 Reports: state and national; publications; national
    - Material for local boards, 1978-1974, 1974 - 1978 (Box-folder 04-05)
      League of Women Voters - National Material for local boards, 1978-1974 Publications: national and state
    - Material on leadership techniques, 1976, 1958, 1958, 1976 (Box-folder 04-06)
      League of Women Voters - National Material on leadership techniques, 1976, 1958 Publications: national and state; reports; national and state; local material
    - Publications, 1977, 1970, 1970, 1977 (Box-folder 04-07)
      League of Women Voters - National Publications, 1977, 1970 Forms for ordering league publications, national and state; catalogs of league publications; publication budget of OVLWV (Oswego Valley League of Women Voters), 1970
  - D. Other Local Chapters, n.d.
    - Interleague organizations, 1976-1968, 1968 - 1976 (04-08)
      League of Women Voters - Other Local Leagues Interleague organizations, 1976-1968 Reports: state
    - Publications, n.d. (Box-folder 04-09)
      League of Women Voters - Other Locals Publications Leaflets and brochures on various topics
- II. Government, 1961 - 1979
  - A. Federal, n.d.
    - Reports from the Hill, 1979-1977, 1969, 1969, 1977-1979 (04-10)
      Government - Federal Reports from the Hill, 1979-1977, 1969 (publication of national)
    - Representative government, 1975-1972, 1972 - 1975 (Box-folder 04-11)
      Government - Federal Representative government, 1975-1972 Reports: national; clippings
    - Executive, 1976-1974, 1968, n.d., 1968, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 04-12)
      Government - Federal Executive, 1976-1974, 1968, n.d. Publications: national; reports; national;outline for OVLWV meeting
    - Legislative branch Congress, 1976-1971, 1971 - 1976 (Box-folder 04-13)
      Government - Federal Legislative branch Congress, 1976-1971 Publications: national; clippings; page from Valley Voter, April 1971
    - Trade, 1979-1972, 1972 - 1979 (Box-folder 04-14)
      Government - Federal Trade, 1979-1972 Publications: national; reports: national and state; clippings: national
    - United Nations, 1971 (Box-folder 04-15)
      Government - Federal United Nations, 1971 Reports: national
  - B. State, n.d.
    - Legislative News, 1979- 1970, 1970 - 1979 (Box-folder 05-01)
      Government - State Legislative News, 1979- 1970 Publications: state (Legislative News, 1978-1973, 1970); reports: state; Cayuga County; clippings: local, national - material on LWV drive in state to pass initiative and Referendum Law and local meeting on the subject.
    - State legislature, 1979-1968, 1968 - 1979 (Box-folder 05-02)
      Government - State State legislature, 1979-1968 Reports: state; clippings; New York State laws; New York State publications; OVLWV meeting publicity.
    - State finances, 1979-1972, 1972 - 1979 (Box-folder 05-03)
      Government - State State finances, 1979-1972 Reports: state; clippings: local; correspondence
    - Constitutional Convention, 1969-1967, 1967 - 1969 (Box-folder 05-04)
      Government - State Constitutional Convention, 1969-1967 Reports: state; New York State documents; correspondence
    - State and local government, 1977-1972, 1972 - 1977 (Box-folder 05-05)
      Government - State State and local government, 1977-1972 Publications: national
    - Apportionment, 1976-1966, 1966 - 1976 (Box-folder 05-06)
      Government - State Apportionment, 1976-1966 Reports: state; correspondence; clippings: local; Oswego County document; OVLWV materials
    - Judicial, 1979-1974, 1969, 1969, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 05-07)
      Government - State Judicial, 1979-1974, 1969 Reports: state; non-league publications (Association of the Bar of the City of New York); clippings
    - Freedom of Information law, 1978 (Box-folder 05-08)
      Government - State Freedom of Information law, 1978 New York State documents; clippings
  - C. Local, n.d.
    - Local government, 1978-1961, 1961 - 1978 (Box-folder 06-01)
      Government - Local Local government, 1978-1961 Publications: national; government documents: state, local (including Oswego County Handbook of Government), 1978; Rules of Order of Business, Oswego County Board of Supervisors, 1961); county budget; county government organizational chart; OVLWV reports; clippings: "Know Your County" series.
    - County chapter, 1978-1969, 1969 - 1978 (Box-folder 06-02)
      Government - Local County chapter, 1978-1969 Clippings; correspondence; OVLWV press releases and meeting material; state documents
    - County Government Day, 1978-1974, 1974 - 1978 (Box-folder 06-03)
      Government - Local County Government Day, 1978-1974 Correspondence; clippings
- III. Elections, 1965 - 1979
  - Elections (general), 1979-1974, 1970, 1970, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 06-04)
    Elections Elections (general), 1979-1974, 1970 Publications: state and national; reports: state and national; clippings: state and national; OVLWV program material; state documents
  - Campaign financing, 1978-1972, 1972 - 1978 (Box-folder 06-05)
    Elections Campaign financing, 1978-1972 Clippings: national and local including OVLWV letters to the editor (especially 1976); publications: national; reports: state and national
  - Voter Services, 1978 (Box-folder 06-06)
    Elections Voter Services, 1978 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications THIS DESCRIPTION APPLIES TO THE VOTER SERVICES SERIES OF FOLDERS 06-06 THROUGH 08-05
  - Voter Services, 1977 (Box-folder 06-07)
    Elections Voter Services, 1977 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes Congressional voting record.
  - Voter Services, 1976 (Box-folder 07-01)
    Elections Voter Services, 1976 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes voting records
  - Voter Services, 1975 (Box-folder 07-02)
    Elections Voter Services, 1975 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications
  - Voter Services, 1974 (Box-folder 07-03)
    Elections Voter Services, 1974 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications
  - Voter Services, 1973 (Box-folder 07-04)
    Elections Voter Services, 1973 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes local government publications; material on school board elections
  - Voter Services, 1972 (Box-folder 07-05)
    Elections Voter Services, 1972 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes material on Fulton school board elections
  - Voter Services, 1971 (Box-folder 08-01)
    Elections Voter Services, 1971 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional correspondence; some non-league publications Includes Fulton school board election
  - Voter Services, 1970 (Box-folder 08-02)
    Elections Voter Services, 1970 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes minutes on OVLWV Voter Services Committee
  - Voter Services, 1969 (Box-folder 08-03)
    Elections Voter Services, 1969 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes primary enrollment books for wards in Fulton and Oswego
  - Voter Services, 1968 (Box-folder 08-04)
    Elections Voter Services, 1968 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes correspondence; material on BOCES referendum
  - Voter Services, 1967-1965, 1965 - 1967 (Box-folder 08-05)
    Elections Voter Services, 1967-1965 Clippings and OVLWV material mainly connected with Meet the Candidates meetings and newspaper section on candidates' positions; reports: state; publications: national; occasional corresponence; some non-league publications Includes minutes of OVLWV Voter Services Committee
- IV. Human Resources, 1969 - 1979
  - General, 1979-1975, 1973, 1969, 1969 - 1979 (Box-folder 08-06)
    Human Resources General, 1979-1975, 1973, 1969 Publications: national; reports: state and national; non-league publications; OVLWV materials for programs; clippings (1976)
  - Schools, 1979- 1969, 1969 - 1979 (Box-folder 08-07)
    Human Resouces Schools, 1979- 1969 Clippings; publications: national; reports: local about school districts in Fulton and Oswego; correspondence
  - Employment, 1979-1971, 1971 - 1979 (Box-folder 09-01)
    Human Resources Employment, 1979-1971 Publications: national; reports: state and national
  - Housing, 1977-1969, 1969 - 1977 (Box-folder 09-02)
    Human Resources Housing, 1977-1969 Publications: national; goverment documents; clippings; material from League of Women Voters of Metropolitan Syracuse
  - Welfare and social services, 1977-1973; 1970-1969, 1969 - 1977 (Box-folder 09-03)
    Human Resources Welfare and social services, 1977-1973; 1970-1969 Publications: national; reports: state; non-league publications; state documents; clippings: local and state
  - Oswego County social services, 1977-1973, 1973 - 1977 (Box-folder 09-04)
    Human Resources Oswego County social services, 1977-1973 Correspondence; clippings; state documents; local documents (including annual report for Oswego County Department of Social Services, 1973 and 1975); OVLWV program material
  - Oswego County Mental Health, 1975-1972, 1972 - 1975 (Box-folder 09-05)
    Human Resources Oswego County Mental Health, 1975-1972 Local government documents (including annual report, 1975 and description of program, 1973); chapter on mental health from OVLWV county study, 1975; OVLWV program material
  - Aging, 1977- 1970, 1970 - 1977 (Box-folder 09-06)
    Human Resources Aging, 1977- 1970 Material from Oswego County Officed for the Aging; state documents; OVLWV program material
  - Women, 1979-1972, 1972 - 1979 (Box-folder 09-07)
    Human Resources Women, 1979-1972 Publications: national; clippings; OVLWV program material (much on ERA)
  - Indians, 1976-1970, 1970 - 1976 (Box-folder 09-08)
    Human Resources Indians, 1976-1970 Reports: national
- V. Land Use, 1968 - 1979
  - General, 1979-1970, 1970 - 1979 (Box-folder 10-01)
    Land Use General, 1979-1970 Publications: national; reports: state; clippings: local, regional, state, national; correspondence
  - Coastal Zone Management, 1979-1977, 1977 - 1979 (Box-folder 10-02)
    Land Use Coastal Zone Management, 1979-1977 Reports: state, national; correspondence; clippings: national, local, regional; OVLWV program materials; material on St. Lawrence River and Eastern Ontario Commission
  - Coastal Management, 1977-1974, 1969, 1969, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 10-03)
    Land Use Coastal Management, 1977-1974, 1969 Same materials
  - Waterfronts, 1979-1972, 1972 - 1979 (Box-folder 10-04)
    Land Use Waterfronts, 1979-1972 Clippings: national, local; state documents; correspondence; material on St. Lawrence River and Eastern Ontario Commission, Save Our Shores and Sea Grant
  - Sea Grant, 1978-1974, 1974 - 1978 (Box-folder 10-05)
    Land Use Sea Grant, 1978-1974 Coastlines, November 12, 1977 -- January 2, 1974 (incomplete); clippings (articles by director of Sea Grant)
  - Community Development block grants, 1978-1975, 1975 - 1978 (Box-folder 11-01)
    Land Use Community Development block grants, 1978-1975 Publications: national; clippings: local
  - Cooperative Extension MIDNY Project, 1978-1968, 1968 - 1978 (11-02)
    Land Use Cooperative Extension MIDNY Project, 1978-1968 Memos; reports; clippings; material on Central New York Consortium and Earth Day, 1970
  - Tug Hill Commission, 1977-1972, 1972 - 1977 (Box-folder 11-03)
    Land Use Tug Hill Commission, 1977-1972 Tug Hill Commission Newsletter (very scattered); state documents; non-league publications; clippings; correpondence
- VI. Environment, 1964 - 1979
  - Pollution (clippings), 1978-1974, 1974 - 1978 (Box-folder 11-04)
    Environment Pollution (clippings), 1978-1974 Clippings: nationa, local. Especially Lake Ontario fishing ban and Pollution Abatement Service, PAS
  - Pollution (clippings), 1973-1969, 1969 - 1973 (Box-folder 11-05)
    Environment Pollution (clippings), 1973-1969 Clippings: national, state and local (includes OVLWV publicity)
  - Magazine articles on pollution, 1973-1969, 1969 - 1973 (Box-folder 11-06)
    Environment Magazine articles on pollution, 1973-1969
  - Pollution, 1977-1970, 1970 - 1977 (Box-folder 11-07)
    Environment Pollution, 1977-1970 Publications: national; non-league; correspondence; state documents; federal documents; state laws
  - Air pollution, 1978-1970, 1970 - 1978 (Box-folder 12-01)
    Environment Air pollution, 1978-1970 Clippings: national; magazine articles; state documents; state laws; correspondence; OVLWV material including local survey forms; material from Oswego City Planning Board
  - Air pollution, 1968-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 12-02)
    Environment Air pollution, 1968-1969, n.d. Clippings: national; magazine articles; state documents; state laws; correspondence; OVLWV material including local survey forms
  - Water pollution, 1979-1971, n.d., 1971 - 1979 (Box-folder 12-03)
    Environment Water pollution, 1979-1971, n.d. Publications: national; correspondence; clippings: national; state laws; materials from New York State Department of Conservation
  - Water pollution, 1970-1964, n.d., 1964 - 1970 (Box-folder 12-04)
    Environment Water pollution, 1970-1964, n.d. Publications: national; correspondence; clippings: national; state laws; materials from the New York State Department of Conservation
  - Waste, 1979-1968, 1968 - 1979 (Box-folder 12-05)
    Environment Waste, 1979-1968 Publications: national; clippings: national, local; state laws; correspondence; non-league publications
  - Recycling, 1979-1966, 1966 - 1979 (Box-folder 13-01)
    Environment Recycling, 1979-1966 Clippings and magazine articles: state, national and local; publications: national; correspondence; material from Ecology Action Coalition
  - Environmental Quality, 1979-1973, 1973 - 1979 (Box-folder 13-02)
    Environment Environmental Quality, 1979-1973 Publications: national; reports: state; clippings: material from New York State Department of Environmental Conservation
  - Environmental Quality, 1972-1965, 1965 - 1972 (Box-folder 13-03)